Md. Asadullah Chowdhury

Address: Shahi Tower, Sector 7, Plot k/25,

Jessore, Khulna, Bangladesh

Phone: 01708746354

Email: asadullah_chowdhury@outlook.com **Github:** https://asadullahchowdhury.github.io

OVERVIEW

Hi! I am Md. Asadullah Chowdhury and I am introducing myself as a Full Stack Web Developer. I have been working as a Web Developer for almost 4 years. I like to work with new technologies and learn new things.

I am experienced with developing professional web applications using PHP, Laravel, ReactJS, Redux, VueJS, Vuex, Vue Router, Angular cli, ngrx and Axios. I have also worked on Laravel VueJS SPA project.

I also have a good understanding of project algorithms which helps me understand and manage project requirements easily and accurately.

I am familiar with Laravel MVC Pattern and the huge package library of Laravel.

I love to study new technologies and develop my skill set and I try to give best effort to my projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/2018 - 12/2018

Junior Software Developer

Freemig inc.

Responsibilities:

- Designing pixel perfect UI from Figma/XD files for different projects.
- Implementing Backend API
- Supporting the Development team on need.

01/2019 - 02/2022

Full Stack Software Developer

Dcastalia

Responsibilities:

- Develop scaled Web applications
 - Manage small development team for assigned project
 - Understanding requirements and creating team work plan

Full Stack Software Developer

freelancer.com Responsibilities:

- Develop scaled Web applications
- Understanding requirements and creating project architecture

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

https://smaty.akg.sa/

Educational Website

Laravel, Laravel Vue Spa, Bootstrap, JQuery

https://elaqa.akg.sa/

Educational Website

Laravel, Laravel Vue Spa, Bootstrap, JQuery

http://www.jilani.com.sa/

Educational Website

Laravel, Laravel Vue Spa, Bootstrap, JQuery

https://me.daaris.com/

Company Portfolio Website

Laravel, Laravel Vue Spa, Bootstrap, JQuery

https://www.habibcomputer.com.bd/

Basic E-commerce site sells Computer accessories

Laravel, Blade Templating, JQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL

https://health-care-authenticati-21857.web.app/

Demo Hospital Website

MERN Stack

https://dazzling-haupia-3fe761.netlify.app/

Demo movie download site

MERN Stack

EDUCATION

2017 - 2020

Bachelor of Science

Manarat International University

Department of Computer Science Engineering

2015 - 2016

H.S.C

Santahar govt. college

2013 - 2014

S.S.C

Sammilani Institution, jessore

SKILLS

General:

JAVASCRIPT, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, NodeJs, Python (Basic)

Cascading Style Sheets Framework:

Bootstrap, Materialize CSS

PHP Framework:

Laravel,

JS Framework:

handlebarsJS, Angular CLI, jQuery, VueJS, ReactJS,

Tools:

Grunt, Gulp, SCSS, LESS, NPM, Apache, Composer

Source Control:

Subversion, GIT

Project Management:

JIRA, Trello

Database:

MySQL, MongoDB

OS:

Linux (Ubuntu20.04), MacOS, Windows

Server Management:

Ubuntu Server

Language Skills

Bangla - (Native Tongue)

English

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Developing skill set and learn new technologies

Watching IMDB Top Rated Movie

Playing Football